# **David Wilder**

# React Native - Full Stack Engineer - Technical Leadership

416-509-8103 - davidedwardwilder@gmail.com - linkedin.com/in/davidedwardwilder

I'm a builder. Front-end, back-end, architecture - coding Uls, creating platforms, and bringing software to life. I love crafting beautiful user experiences out of high-fidelity mockups.

Passionate full stack engineer and manager with over ten years of experience, four years of experience with React / React Native, and two years of experience in technical leadership. I have lead cross-functional teams to deliver complex projects in a multi-tenant SaaS platform serving 100k+ customers. I love leading and mentoring, but I need to build.

# **Professional Experience**

## Mercatus Technologies (Toronto) · 2017 - 2024

Engineering Manager • 2023 - 2024

- \* Managed a team of software engineers and QAs to deliver ad network and product sampling projects spanning front end web, mobile, multiple backend services, data engineering, and third party integrations.
- \* Provided architectural guidance, adherence to code quality standards, and code review for core React Native application.

Team Lead, Mobile • 2022 - 2023

- \* Lead redevelopment of core white label mobile application resulting in 28% increase in conversion rate for grocery clients, with the Sr Engineering Manager.
- \* Lead Redux refactoring to implement RTK slices and API transforms resulting in significant performance gains.
- \* Achieved 90%+ sprint completion rate as Scrum Master for a multidisciplinary team of engineers, supporting solution design, task management, and code delivery.

Software Engineer, Mobile • 2017 - 2022

- \* Built multiple features for white label e-commerce React Native mobile application: design system, theming, custom fonts; flyers; configurable home screen, product promotions and merchandising.
- \* Maintained 100% unit test coverage for React Native contributions.
- \* Built PoC for internal documentation website using Docusaurus.
- \* Delivered on multiple projects for white label e-commerce Ionic/AngularJS application: menu configuration and redesign; product redesigns; search history & suggestion; product options wizard; EBT payment with Fiserv; translation/localization import/export to CSV.

#### Brainrider (Toronto) · 2016 - 2017

Web Developer

- \* Created wireframes, developed and modified WordPress themes and plugins for B2B clients.
- \* Ensured HTML5 templates met SEO, accessibility and Google PageSpeed requirements.
- \* Utilized frameworks, build processes, and animations to optimize development and UX.

### Self Employed (Toronto) · 2007 - 2019

UX Design and Web Developer

- \* Created wireframes, site maps, user flows and documentation for six large scale web and mobile applications, including requirements gathering with multiple clients.
- \* Built a responsive WordPress website for autism awareness, integrating a Google Map showing national flags for 80+ destinations of a round the world trip.
- \* Built two fundraising web applications, designed and implemented database structure, authentication, account management, Stripe payment integration and custom tax receipts.
- \* Developed free and paid WordPress plugins, including the top ranked mortgage calculator plugin with 60k+ downloads and 10k+ install at the time of selling the rights to the plugin.

#### Skills

Leadership • Communication • Emotional Intelligence • Mentoring/Coaching • Agile/Scrum

HTML5 • CSS • Sass • JavaScript • TypeScript • React • React Native • Redux • RTK • Redux Observable • RxJS • Bootstrap • ¡Query • Scroll Magic • Ionic/AngularJS • Jest

PHP • MySQL • Python • NodeJS • Express • MongoDB • yarn • GulpJS • GruntJS • PHPUnit

Git • Github • Bitbucket • SVN SSH • FTP • Plesk • cPanel

Visual Studio Code • Xcode • Android Studio Figma • Sketch • Balsamiq

# **Training & Education**

Berteig Consulting Inc • 2022: Scrum Master Training & CSM

B.Sc. University of Toronto • 2002: Physics Major & Math Minor

\* NSERC Scholarship Recipient • 2000: Study of quasi-biennial oscillation using computer modelling and data analysis.

## Volunteer

Nalandabodhi Foundation • 2013 - 2020: Buddhist meditation & study group facilitator